<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NSXT on netmemo.github.io</title>
    <link>https://netmemo.github.io/tags/nsxt/</link>
    <description>Recent content in NSXT on netmemo.github.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>No&amp;euml;l Boul&amp;egrave;ne &amp;copy; 2021. This blog is strictly personnal and opinions expressed here are only mine and doesn&amp;#39;t reflect those of my past, current or futur employers. No warranty whatsoever is made that any of the posts are accurate. There is absolutely no assurance (apart from author&amp;acute;s professional integrity) that any statement contained in a post is true, correct or precise.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 19:17:50 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://netmemo.github.io/tags/nsxt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>NSX-T Uplinks Memo</title>
      <link>https://netmemo.github.io/post/nsx-t-uplinks-memo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 19:17:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netmemo.github.io/post/nsx-t-uplinks-memo/</guid>
      <description>This is a memo regarding NSX-T uplinks. I think this is the most confusing and difficult part to understand in NSX-T. This post is made from 3 sections, Diagram with a more visual approach, Component with remarks/comments on uplinks components and a Q&amp;amp;A section based on questions I was asking myself. You can find duplicate information but slightly rephrased in every section. I kept it that way as some time some form are easier to understand than other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NSX-T Firewall rules as code with Terraform</title>
      <link>https://netmemo.github.io/post/nsxt-tf-firewall/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 19:03:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netmemo.github.io/post/nsxt-tf-firewall/</guid>
      <description>This article is to show an example of how to manage NSX-T firewall rules as a code through Terraform. You can find the project on my github account : nsxt-frac-tf-cm and nsxt-frac-tf-rm
I will describe the structure of the project, how it works, the data model, the Terraform code explanation and finish with an example.
Structure of the project The diagram below shows a summary of how I organized the project in order to fully use infrastructre as code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform Refactoring State File</title>
      <link>https://netmemo.github.io/post/terraform-refactoring-state-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 21:56:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netmemo.github.io/post/terraform-refactoring-state-file/</guid>
      <description>https://www.terraform.io/docs/cli/commands/state/mv.html
On windows :
terraform state mv nsxt_policy_security_policy.policy1 nsxt_policy_security_policy.policies[\&amp;ldquo;policy1\&amp;ldquo;]  It move resources from a construct like this
locals { policy1= { rule1 = { source = [&amp;quot;src1&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;src2&amp;quot;] } } policy2 = { rule1 = { source = [&amp;quot;src3&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;src4&amp;quot;] } } }  To a structure like this
locals { policies = { policy1 = { rule1 = { source = [&amp;quot;src1&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;src2&amp;quot;] } } policy2 = { rule2 = { source = [&amp;quot;src3&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;src4&amp;quot;] } } } }  The main moving from</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create portable Terraform and plugins with Terraform-bundle for Windows</title>
      <link>https://netmemo.github.io/post/tf-bundle-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 21:32:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netmemo.github.io/post/tf-bundle-windows/</guid>
      <description>The steps below are what I have followed to create a terraform-bundle to use terraform with non default providers on a server that doesn&amp;rsquo;t have access to Internet. You can find the tool explanation in the below link.
https://github.com/hashicorp/terraform/tree/master/tools/terraform-bundle
installation of golang with msi downloaded here
https://golang.org/doc/install
Clone the terraform repository to get the tool
https://github.com/hashicorp/terraform.git
cd terraform-master go install .\tools\terraform-bundle  Check the terraform version C:\Users\noyel\Desktop\tfforeach\nsxt&amp;gt;terraform version Terraform v0.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>