<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cloud on netmemo.github.io</title>
    <link>https://netmemo.github.io/categories/cloud/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cloud on netmemo.github.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>No&amp;euml;l Boul&amp;egrave;ne &amp;copy; 2021. This blog is strictly personnal and opinions expressed here are only mine and doesn&amp;#39;t reflect those of my past, current or futur employers. No warranty whatsoever is made that any of the posts are accurate. There is absolutely no assurance (apart from author&amp;acute;s professional integrity) that any statement contained in a post is true, correct or precise.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 18:00:45 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://netmemo.github.io/categories/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Can we ping an AWS Lambda function ?</title>
      <link>https://netmemo.github.io/post/lambdaping/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 18:00:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netmemo.github.io/post/lambdaping/</guid>
      <description>Context Can we ping the ENI of an AWS Lambda function within the VPC ? While the answer can be obvious the path to get it was insightful for me and has helped me to be more comfortable with :
 AWS IAM.
 AWS Lambdas function.
 AWS Static IP addresses and AWS default subnets.
  This test can be performed with the AWS free tier. You will find the Terraform scripts here : Lambda Ping</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github Actions with Terraform Cloud for CI/CD of NSX-T</title>
      <link>https://netmemo.github.io/post/tf-gha-nsxt-cicd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 14:02:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netmemo.github.io/post/tf-gha-nsxt-cicd/</guid>
      <description>This post is to show an example of using CI/CD with Terraform Cloud and Github Actions in order to have a better NetDevOps approach by doing NSX-T Network Infrastructure as code (IaC). It&amp;rsquo;s almost a bingo, I think I have most of the buzz words of these last years :)
I will describe the structure of the project, the project components, the project workflow and finish with how to test this project.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>