<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NSX-T on netmemo.github.io</title>
    <link>https://netmemo.github.io/tags/nsx-t/</link>
    <description>Recent content in NSX-T on netmemo.github.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>No&amp;euml;l Boul&amp;egrave;ne &amp;copy; 2021. This blog is strictly personnal and opinions expressed here are only mine and doesn&amp;#39;t reflect those of my past, current or futur employers. No warranty whatsoever is made that any of the posts are accurate. There is absolutely no assurance (apart from author&amp;acute;s professional integrity) that any statement contained in a post is true, correct or precise.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 19:17:50 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://netmemo.github.io/tags/nsx-t/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>NSX-T Uplinks Memo</title>
      <link>https://netmemo.github.io/post/nsx-t-uplinks-memo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 19:17:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netmemo.github.io/post/nsx-t-uplinks-memo/</guid>
      <description>This is a memo regarding NSX-T uplinks. I think this is the most confusing and difficult part to understand in NSX-T. This post is made of 3 sections, Diagram with a more visual approach, Component with remarks/comments on uplinks components and a Q&amp;amp;A section based on questions I was asking myself. You can find duplicate information but slightly rephrased in every section. I kept it that way as some time some form are easier to understand than other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github Actions with Terraform Cloud for CI/CD of NSX-T</title>
      <link>https://netmemo.github.io/post/tf-gha-nsxt-cicd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 14:02:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netmemo.github.io/post/tf-gha-nsxt-cicd/</guid>
      <description>This post is to show an example of using CI/CD with Terraform Cloud and Github Actions in order to have a better NetDevOps approach by doing NSX-T Network Infrastructure as code (IaC). It&amp;rsquo;s almost a bingo, I think I have most of the buzz words of these last years :)
I will describe the structure of the project, the project components, the project workflow and finish with how to test this project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform nested for_each for NSX-T with dynamic</title>
      <link>https://netmemo.github.io/post/tf-nsxt-nested-for-each/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 22:06:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netmemo.github.io/post/tf-nsxt-nested-for-each/</guid>
      <description>The post below shows how to create security policy groups for NSX-T with Terraform nested for_each loop and dynamic.
The variables are made from one map of list. Each list represents one group composed of tags.
https://www.hashicorp.com/blog/hashicorp-terraform-0-12-preview-for-and-for-each
variable &amp;quot;mapgroups&amp;quot; { type	= map default	= { NBO	= [&amp;quot;NBO&amp;quot;] NBO-PROD	= [&amp;quot;NBO&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;PROD&amp;quot;] } } resource &amp;quot;nsxt_policy_group&amp;quot; &amp;quot;nbogroups&amp;quot; { for_each	= var.mapgroups display_name	= each.key criteria { dynamic &amp;quot;condition&amp;quot; { for_each = each.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>